Then press SHIFT W to show all the panels
Then the panels that were anti-activated before activation
After activation, you can see that because there was no constraint when anti-activation before
Causing it to have an intersection with the panels inside
First of all, we can see that the particle diameter of the inner panel is relatively small, which is 8
The particle diameter of the outer panel is 20
The network gap is far from enough
So let's reduce the particle diameter of the outer panel to 10
Reduce the conflict thickness to 1
Then we select all the shoulder straps
Then set their levels to 1 in the attribute editor
The default level of the panel is 0
After we start the simulation, the panels with higher levels will automatically be worn on the outside of the panels with lower levels
After the shoulder strap part is worn out
We press CTRL A to select all the panels
Then activate the simulation and interact with each other
After the simulation is done, press CTRL A to select all the panels
We return the level of the panels to 0
Then press the grid line again to simulate
Then we freeze these panels
Then we want to do the details of the shoulder strap part
First of all, the joint edge can be generated by sewing a longer panel on a shorter panel
Then the joint edge will be generated
So the joint edge can be created by sewing a shorter panel on a shorter panel
Then we use the rectangle tool
In the 2D window, click and drag to draw a rectangle that is longer than before
Then use the line powder tool to sew the sides of the two panels together
Then use the adjustment panel tool to select the entire joint edge panel
Press CTRL D
Click in the 2D window to arrange
Press the control key to simulate
Sew the joint edge
Because our current panel has a larger particle diameter
So its fold is not very detailed
We will reduce the particle diameter
Reduce the
Then copy and paste this pair of joint edges
Then select the level in the 3D space and turn it over
Turn them over to the back
Then drag these two panels in the 3D space
Then take the other group of the back panel
The joint edge will also automatically generate a seam line
Then because we are now in the back of the virtual model
So if we want to match the panel is a bit difficult
You can select the final panel in the 3D window
Then arrange them in the 2D window
Then create a seam line
Or you can directly use the 3D sewing tool in the 3D window
For example, the 3D sewing tool
Click on the joint edge and then click on the shoulder strap
Then press the control key to start simulation
Then we are going to sew the bottom of the side of the contract here on the belt, so here we are going to use the free sewing tool.
After using the free sewing tool, first create the first section of the sewing line.
Then when our mouse stop at the previous shoulder strap of this set of sewing lines, we can find another sewing line.
Then start from the end of this sewing line to create the other half of the sewing line.
The back here is the same, first click from the inside point to create the first set of sewing lines.
Then find the corresponding position on the belt, click, and then also sew outward.
Be careful that the direction is correct.
After that, we are going to use the line sewing tool to sew the side of the contract.
Because one side of the contract is seen from the front, and the other is seen from the back.
So if we point it in the opposite direction, these two sewing lines, one is to click on the left side, and the other is to click on the right side.
As for the belt, we can see that we used free sewing before.
Both are from close to the shoulder strap.
Because the shoulder strap here, we know which point it is.
So we start from the end point and sew to the other side.
Then let's adjust the side of the contract.
First, drag the top point to the outside.
During the process of dragging outward, press the Shift key to move in the direction of the reference lines.
In the process of this operation, press the right mouse button to enter the specific number.
Then let's adjust the back.
We can click on this side to change in 3D space.
Find this point according to the blue index point.
Then the same.
Press the Shift key to remove the point.
Then press the right mouse button to enter the specific number.
Ensure that the input number is adjusted the same as the front piece.
If you need it, you can also widen the bottom plate here.
Or take it in a little bit.
Note that the bottom plate has a sewing line.
So if we modify the bottom plate, don't forget to adjust the sewing line in the corresponding position with the writing sewing tool.
It's the same as our previous operation on the shoulder strap.
Then we can freeze the patterned pattern on the shoulder.
Next, we are going to make the padded pattern on the chest.
Because there is no cut on this line on the whole belt pattern,
we are going to use the writing sewing line tool.
The mark near the sewing line is the starting point of the sewing line.
The distance is the end point of the sewing line.
So when we choose the sewing line, right-click and select the end point of the sewing line.
Then click the add point.
Next, when we switch to the adjustment pattern tool, we will see that there is actually a straight line point here.
Then we draw a rectangle that is almost wide according to the position of this straight line point.
We can set the height of this rectangle at will.
In the editing process, you can refer to the pink guide line.
After adjusting, select the line in front and right-click and select the symmetry to open the edit sewing line function.
Then this pattern, although it is a complete pattern,
the left and right sides of this pattern are symmetrical.
As long as we sew the one side and the symmetrical pattern,
the other side will also automatically generate a sewing line.
Next, let's take a look at the side line.
The side line, because there is no cut on the side,
we can't use the sewing line tool.
So we use the free sewing tool.
First, select the part of the cloth here.
Then go to the shoulder strap here, click the starting point, click the end point.
Because we have placed it in the 3D space before,
so just press the control key to simulate it.
After the simulation is done,
activate all the cold plates next to it to simulate.
After the simulation, you will see that the position of the shoulder strap and the seam line is deformed.
So here we need to adjust the width of the seam line.
The width of the bottom plate is correct,
but because the shoulder strap is stretched a little in the middle part,
so we have to move the side point out a little.
After moving, refer to the position in the 3D space.
We can stretch this plate a little longer.
After stretching,
because we created a free sewing line before,
so we need to press the control key B,
which is the editing sewing line tool,
to drag the edge of the sewing line to the support point of the blue length corresponding to it.
After that, we can repeat this step
until the shoulder strap reaches the height we want.
Of course, in the process of modification,
you can also adjust the width of the shoulder strap according to your needs.
Also, don't forget to modify the side of the plate.
After that, the seam line on the side also needs to match.
If, like in the video,
there are some wrinkles on the chest,
we can just put this widened part in a little more.
After that, we move the rest of the shoulder strap and the seam line together to simulate.
For the frozen plate,
we can choose to activate or move it back to its original state.
After the simulation is complete,
we select all the plates and freeze them together.